《哥谭》前情提要
Previously on Gotham...
该死
Oh, crud.
他杀了我母亲  吉姆
He killed my mother, Jim.
他叫人当着我的面杀了她
He had her murdered in front of me.
我会杀了你的
I'm going to kill you.
我好像有发现
I think I found something.
这是他被杀的那周
The week of his murder,
他约好去见一个叫凯伦·詹宁斯的女人
he was supposed to meet a woman named Karen Jennings
谈关于"松林农场"的事
about something called "Pinewood Farms."
松林农场是韦恩集团旗下的
Pinewood Farms was a bioengineering program
生物工程项目
at Wayne Enterprises.
这个项目又开始运行了吧
It started up again, didn't it?
所以我父亲才在那么多年后又来见你
That's why my father came to see you after all those years.
凯伦·詹妮斯一进黑门监狱就必死无疑
Karen Jennings's gonna be dead the minute she hits Blackgate Prison.
所以我们得去劫囚
That's why we're gonna break her out.
雇"火柴"马龙杀你父母的人
The man who contracted Matches Malone to kill your parents
自称"哲学家"
called himself The Philosopher.
我敢打赌  此人就是
And I'd be willing to bet that this is the man
松林幕后的黑手
who was behind Pinewood.
雨果·斯特兰奇
Hugo Strange.
哲学家
The Philosopher.
他现在是阿卡姆的主管
He runs Arkham now.
我们复活了一个人
We brought someone back.
死亡天使阿泽瑞尔
Azrael...
我们真做到了
We actually did it.
仅供学习  禁止商用  更多影视
登陆www.ZiMuZu.tv
翻译 小胖纸Amy   辰星晓Reginamoon   Silence   charcie
翻译 大K   小酸奶!   DustD   草草   后期 饿得慌
时间轴 风吹来的那片云   校对&总监 草草
向我集结
Rally to me.
圣杜马会拯救我们
St. Dumas will deliver us.
杜马会拯救我们
Dumas will deliver us.
集结
Rally.
异教徒
Heathens.
圣杜马会保护我们
And Dumas will protect us.
异教徒
Heathens,
拜偶像者
idolaters,
撒旦之子  准备受死吧
Spawn of Satan, prepare to die!
不
No. No.
不要这样  妹妹
No, don't. Please. Sister?
和我说话  拜托  和我说话吧
Speak to me, please. Please speak to me.
你们是谁
Who are you?
Who are you?!
-他昨天醒来后有任何好转吗  -没
- Has there been any improvement since he woke up yesterday? - No.
但他棒极了  不是吗
But he's wonderful, isn't he?
你们是谁
Who are you?
Who are you?!
壮如牛  快如蛇
Strong as an ox, fast as a snake.
疯透顶
Mad as a hatter.
如果这些死人醒来后都疯了
There's not much use bringing back the dead
那还有什么意义
if they come back crazy.
他没疯
Oh, he's not crazy.
他只是不知道自己是谁
He just doesn't know who he is.
起死回生后  他心智紊乱
His psyche can't reconcile being brought back from the dead.
精神受挫  记忆只剩下碎片
It's fractured, grasping at fragmented memories.
他写在墙上的字
The text that he has written on the walls
都是这本书里的诗
are all verses from this book.
《圣杜马教义与制度》
The Will and Order of St. Dumas.
盖勒文家族起源于12世纪
The Galavan family is proudly descended
十字军骑士  他们对此很自豪
from 12th century crusading knights.
这是他们的圣书
This is their sacred text.
显然  我们的病人把整本书都记下来了
Evidently, our patient has memorized the whole book.
他的大脑在努力重建一个条理清晰的自我
His brain is struggling to rebuild a coherent self,
但他用错"零件"了
but he's using the wrong parts.
那怎么治愈他
So what's the cure?
问得好
Good question.
怎么了
What is it?
戈登先生
Mr. Gordon.
斯特兰奇教授
Professor Strange.
抱歉突然拜访
Sorry to drop by unexpected.
没关系  请坐
Oh, not at all. Please, have a seat.
什么风把你给吹来了
To what do I owe the pleasure?
一名委托人雇我调查一些事
I've been hired by a client to look into something.
我希望你能帮到我
I was hoping you could help me with it.
当然
Of course.
这是凯伦·詹宁斯
This is Karen Jennings.
她昨晚被杀害了
She was murdered last night.
太不幸了
Oh, how tragic.
她是韦恩集团以前
She was a test subject
一个叫"松林农场"项目的实验对象
in an old Wayne Enterprises program called Pinewood Farms.
凯伦死前提到
Before she passed, Karen mentioned
你参与了这个项目
you were involved with the program.
那是很久以前的事了
That was a long time ago.
回想一下
Try and remember.
如果可以的话
If you can.
"松林农场"项目是托马斯·韦恩发起的
Pinewood Farms was started by Thomas Wayne
力图从基因层面上治愈人类的重大疾患
in an attempt to cure humanity's greatest ailments on the genetic level--
比如衰老  疾病
old age, disease,
甚至是死亡
even death.
但实际情况并非如此  不是吗
But that's not what happened, is it?
凯伦说这个项目试图扮演上帝
Karen said the program tried to play God,
最终你只造出了怪物
and you ended up creating monsters.
我只是个科研人员
I was just a researcher
直到事情无法挽回时才发现此事
with no knowledge of that until it was too late.
凭你的技术和专业知识
A man of your skill and expertise
只是个小科研人员
a lowly researcher.
我觉得这难以置信
Find that hard to believe.
但这是事实
But it's true.
韦恩先生善于分隔他生活中的不同部分
Mr. Wayne excelled at compartmentalizing every aspect of his life.
在松林农场
Within Pinewood,
左手通常不知道右手在做什么
the left hand often didn't know what the right was doing.
他骗了我们所有人
He lied to us all.
没多少人会把你看作是此事的受害者
Not many people would see you as the victim here.
我是逼迫托马斯·韦恩关闭这个项目的人之一
I was one of the ones who forced Thomas Wayne to shut down the program,
但那个时候...
but by then...
已经有太多人受到了伤害
so many people had been hurt.
我有个理论
I have a theory.
我认为之前经营松林农场的人是你
I believe you ran Pinewood Farms.
我认为你重启了这个项目
I believe you've restarted the program,
而我想知道...
and I would like to know...
你到底是为什么而来  戈登先生
Why are you really here, Mr. Gordon?
什么意思
Excuse me?
这座城市背弃了你
This whole city has turned its back on you,
尽管你一次又一次奋不顾身地拯救它
despite you risking your life to save it over and over again.
我不是来进行心理咨询的  教授
I'm not here for a therapy session, Professor.
的确  这更像是一场审问
No. It's more like an interrogation
发问的是一个不再是警察的人
by a man who is no longer a police officer.
此人已经没有权利要求别人做出回答了
Who no longer has the right to demand answers.
你能坐在那张椅子上的唯一原因
The only reason you're sitting in that chair
是因为我允许你
is because I allow it.
所以我问问你
So let me ask you,
你是  为什么
why... are... you...
而来
here?
像我之前说的  我是受人之托
Like I said, I have a client.
我猜是布鲁斯·韦恩吧
Bruce Wayne, I suppose.
这是一份工作吗
So it's a job?
你来这里是为了挣房租吗
You're here to pay the rent?
肯定不是
Surely not.
这一年来  你的一切遭遇
All that's happened to you this last year.
英雄警察被判谋杀
Hero cop found guilty of murder.
含冤关进黑门监狱
Sentenced unjustly to Blackgate.
如今归来  你还剩什么呢
And now you return to what?
你已经失去了一切
You've lost everything.
你是在试图弥补你过去的罪恶
You're trying to make up for the sins of your past,
而你觉得这个案子能以某种方式
and you believe that this case will somehow
给你带来个人的救赎
bring about your own personal redemption.
不是的
No.
你做这件事不是为了你的委托人
You're not doing this for your client.
而是为你了自己
You're doing this for yourself.
你错了
You're wrong.
你刚刚做了一些微表情
You just exhibited several tells--
人们撒谎时会不自觉做出的
facial ticks expressions and eye movements
出卖他们内心活动的面部表情
that people involuntarily betray themselves with
和眼部动作
when they lie.
我们说说维克多·弗莱斯吧
Let's talk about Victor Fries.
维克多·弗莱斯已经死了  戈登先生
Victor Fries is dead, Mr. Gordon.
是吗  我昨晚看见他了
Really? I saw him last night.
这是不可能的
That's impossible.
这是地检官丹特
This is a court order
签署的开棺验明弗莱斯尸体的法庭判令
signed by District Attorney Dent to exhume Fries' body.
尸体埋在哪里
Where is it buried?
他被火化了
He was cremated.
谢谢你
Thank you.
谢什么
For what?
我也会看微表情
I can read tells, too.
你在撒谎
You're lying.
我需要确定你就是幕后主使
I needed to be sure you were behind all this,
现在我确定了
and now I am.
哥谭
第二季  第十九集
别撒谎  我听到了
Don't lie! I heard you!
别  求你
Don't. Please.
-这就对了  -别
- There you go. - Don't.
动手吧  干掉他
Please do! Squeeze the life from him!
杀了他  快动手
Kill him! Kill him now!
-你俩又打架了吗  -他说我胖
- Are you two fighting again? - He called me fat!
我什么也没说  不是我
I didn't do anything! It wasn't... m-me!
是露西
It was Lucy.
又是那个第五人格
The fifth personality again.
态度真是恶劣
Such a nasty attitude.
这事挺复杂
See, this gets complicated.
露西存在于他脑内
See, Lucy is in his head,
因为鲁迪患有多重人格
'cause Rudy has what's called multiple personality...
在他脑子里
In his head?!
-那我就把她拉出来  -别别别
- Then I'll pull her out! - No. No, no, no, no, no.
她只是个鬼魂
She's... she's a... she's a ghost.
-鬼...  -没错
- A gho... - Yes.
而且她逼鲁迪说一些他不愿说的话
And she makes Rudy say things that he doesn't want to say.
我看到她了
I can see her.
露西
Lucy?
你胆子不小啊
You've... got some nerve.
逼老鲁迪说那种话
Making old Rudy say things like that.
你知道赫尔辛格一点也不胖
You know that Helzinger is not fat.
其实  你说过赫尔辛格很帅
In fact, you said that Helzinger was handsome.
别推我
Don't you shove me!
她打了我一巴掌
She slapped me.
我告诉你  露西
Now I'll tell you something, Lucy.
离鲁迪远点
You will leave Rudy alone.
如果你再回来
And if you come back here again,
就得先过我这关
you'll have to deal with me.
谢谢你  露西
Thank you, Lucy.
那些话真是她逼你说的吗
She really made you say all that?
是的  不
Y-Yeah. Wa...
不
wa...
不是我说的
wasn't me.
抱歉
Sorry.
露西觉得我很帅吗
Lucy thinks I'm handsome?
对吧  露...
Is that right, Lu...?
他怎么来了
What is he doing here?
你好啊  吉米
Hello, Jimmy.
下地狱吧  爱德
Go to hell, Ed.
你已经把我扔在那里了
Oh, you've already put me there.
这里就是地狱
Here.
但不会太久的  朋友
But not for long, my friend.
我会逃出升天的
I'll find my way out.
因为这地方就是个大谜题
'Cause this place is just one big puzzle,
而谜题是我的特长
and puzzles are my forte.
没人能打败我
Nobody beats me.
我就打败了你
I did.
永别了  爱德
See you never, Ed.
那只是你的想法
That's what you think.
我感觉他会给我们惹大麻烦
I have the feeling he's going to be more than a simple nuisance.
不会受贿  也别想轻易引开他的注意
Not the type to be bribed, nor distracted easily.
确实
Indeed.
非常有趣
Very interesting.
什么东西没有手却会来敲你的门
What has no hands but might knock on your door,
而你最好给它开门
and you better open up if it does?
戈登先生持续的干扰
Mr. Gordon's continued interference threatens
可能会拖慢我们  而我们就要登顶了
to slow us down when we're about to reach our finest moment.
他能做的不止如此
He'll do more than that.
尼格玛先生
Mr. Nygma.
偷听可是无礼且不明智的
Eavesdropping is rude and unwise.
偷听是有意的  而我只是...
Eavesdropping implies intent, and I mostly...
无意中听到了
accidentally overheard.
听到了什么
Overheard what?
吉姆·戈登  "麻烦"
Jim Gordon, the word nuisance.
听起来很耳熟
Sounds familiar.
也许和你释放企鹅
Probably has something to do with your
和戈登的前未婚妻有关
releasing Penguin and Gordon's ex-fiancée.
也许
Probably.
我可以帮你  搞定他
I can help you... take him down.
我了解吉姆·戈登的一切
I know everything about Jim Gordon.
如果你让我出去
If you let me out of here,
或许我们可以坐在你的办公室里...
we could probably just sit down in your office...
尼格玛先生  你帮不了我
Mr. Nygma, you can't help me.
我是来帮你的
I'm here to help you.
这是我们已经安排好的角色
Those are the roles that were defined for the two of us.
-我还有其他要事...  -不  听着
- Now, there's another pressing matter... - No. Listen. I-I...
我会操纵他人
I can manipulate people.
我对戈登做过一次  我还能再做一次
I did it to Gordon once, and I can do it again,
因为人的大脑仅仅是个谜题
'cause peoples' brains are just a mystery,
一旦你解开了
and once you figure it out...
看着
Look.
赫尔辛格
Helzinger?
因为母亲的霸道而无法忍受批评
Can't stand criticism because of an overbearing mother.
渴望爱与肯定
Wants love and approval.
得不到就会发疯  所以我给了他
Gets mad when he doesn't get it, so I give it.
谢谢你
Oh, thank you!
莎伦
Sharon.
因强迫性精神障碍而产生盗窃癖
Kleptomaniacal due to obsessive-compulsive disorder.
只要给她能集中注意力的东西就行
Just give her something to concentrate on.
还有  诺顿
And... and Norton.
完全不懂得尊重界线
Serious boundary issues.
有虐待  暴力还有食人倾向
Prone to torture, violence and cannibalism.
除非他觉得他是你的朋友
Unless he thinks he's your friend!
给我的
For me?
重点是  每个人都有故事
My point is, everyone has a story,
而他们只是想被倾听  我的天
and they just want to be listened to. My God!
我才该做心理医生
I should be the shrink!
你说什么
What did you say?
抱歉  是不是太过火了
I'm sorry. Was that too far?
每个人都有故事
Everybody has a story.
没错  尼格玛先生
That's it. Mr. Nygma,
你还真是帮了大忙
you've actually been very helpful.
我知道了  皮博迪
I have it, Peabody.
我知道怎么治我们最有价值的病人了
I have the cure for our prize patient.
说说吧
Do tell.
什么是身份
What is an identity?
什么是自我意识
What is a sense of self?
那是人类对自我讲述的故事
It is a story that we humans tell ourselves.
我们得给他一个伟大的英雄故事
We have got to give him a great, heroic story.
我们得给他大剂量的氯丙嗪[强力镇静剂]
We need to give him a good heroic dose of Thorazine,
不过你说了算
but you're the boss.
棒极了
Perfect.
-棒极了  -先生
- Perfect! - Sir?
阿泽瑞尔
先生  停下
Sir? Stop!
他很危险
He's dangerous!
人呢
Hello?
所有安保人员立刻来复苏实验室
I need all available security to the reanimation lab now!
别  别让他们进来
No! Do not let them in!
别干涉我们
Do not interfere!
儿子
My son.
儿子  住手
My son, please stop.
你为何要抛弃我
Why have you forsaken me?
你忘记准则了吗
Have you forgotten the code?
你是谁
Who are you?
我可怜亲爱的儿子
My poor, dear son.
你以为我是谁
Who do you think I am?
你儿子
Your son?
你是我父亲
You're my father?
还能是谁
Who else?
我注视你时  你感觉不到父亲的爱吗
Don't you feel a father's love when I look into your eyes?
我在哪
Where am I?
我是出了什么事
What has happened to me?!
我是怎么了
What happened to me?
我怎么记不起自己的名字
Why don't I know my name?
儿子
My son...
冷静下来
Calm your heart.
你被恶魔带去了死亡之地
Demons took you to the land of death
给你的灵魂施了魔法
and bewitched your soul,
但我救活了你
but I brought you back to life.
你得到了救赎
You are the redeemed one.
我叫什么
What is my name?
你自己知道
You know your name.
不  不对
No. No.
我有另一个人生
There is another life.
有妹妹  高塔
There is a sister, a high tower.
不不  那是魔法的蛊惑
No, no, no, no, no. Bewitchment.
塞进你头脑里的虚假记忆
False memories put into your head.
我是你父亲  你的主人
I am your father and your lord.
重生之人
And he who has another birth,
逃离了死亡冰冷的魔爪
brought forth from the cold grasp of death
他将再次崛起  听从我的命令
shall rise again and serve my Order.
我之言  你之命
I say this, and it becomes.
我要给他的名就是...
And I will give him the name of...
死亡天使阿泽瑞尔
Azrael!
没错
Yes!
我...是死亡天使
I... am Azrael!
杜马我主
My Lord Dumas.
给我命令吧
Command me.
是他雇人杀了我父母吗
This man ordered my parents' death?
你确定吗
You're sure?
你父母的死因  有一部分在于他
I know he was part of the reason they were killed.
为什么没逮捕他
Why is he not under arrest?
没那么简单  猛男
It's not so simple, hoss.
证据不足  没法申请逮捕令
The evidence we have is far too tenuous for a warrant.
是久远的传闻  又不是指纹证据
It's ancient hearsay, not fingerprints.
唯一的证人还死了
Only witness is dead.
巴恩斯都不会拒绝
Barnes wouldn't even say no.
他只会以为我疯了
He would just look at me like I was nuts.
我受够了
I'm sick of this.
我们知道斯特兰奇在哪
We know where Strange is,
知道他此刻正在伤害别人
we know he's hurting people right now,
你俩却在这儿打官腔
and you two are talking about politics with your boss
想让上司签什么逮捕令
and then getting a piece of paper signed.
-这是正规流程  布鲁斯  -为什么
- This is the way it works, Bruce. - Why?
你都不是警察了
You're not a cop anymore.
让我们单独谈下
Give us a sec?
布鲁斯  我知道你很沮丧
Bruce, I know you're frustrated,
但我们得通过正当手段解决此事
but we need to do this the right way.
正当手段
The right way?
正当手段在盖勒文身上失败了多少次
And how many times did that fail with Galavan?
那不一样
It's not the same.
他一再凌驾于法律之上
He bent and broke the law over and over again,
斯特兰奇也是如此
and Strange is doing the same thing.
此人杀了凯伦  也许还杀了我父母
This man killed Karen, maybe my parents.
听着  我很感激你为我做的一切
Look, I-I appreciate everything that you've done for me.
但我怕我们还是在走以前的老路
But I fear we are going down the same path as before,
根本讨不回公道  除非
and we won't get justice unless...
除非怎样
Unless what?
像你对付盖勒文那样
What you did to Galavan.
你不得不做的事
What you knew you had to do,
以绕过官僚主义和繁文缛节
because of the bureaucracy and the red tape.
我不得不做的事
What I had to do?
我选择冷血地杀死了一个人
I chose to kill a man in cold blood,
越过那道界线  是错的
and it was the wrong choice, crossing that line.
你会一再为此付出代价
You'll pay for it over and over again,
就如我那样
like I have been.
我现在还在付出代价
Like I still am.
这会让你变成你努力对抗的邪恶
And it will make you more like the evil you're trying to fight.
你得比那强
You need to be better.
明白吗
Do you understand me?
再忍一阵子
Just hold out a little bit longer.
我们会搞定巴恩斯
We'll work on Barnes,
让他签发逮捕令
get him to sign off on a warrant
将斯特兰奇永远关进监狱
and put Strange away for good.
用正当手段
The right way.
阿卡姆疯人院
因担心由于缺乏领导
Fearing the knights had become soft
骑士们已变得软弱无能
and weak from lack of leadership,
杜马大人与骑士团决裂
Lord Dumas split from among them
建立了新的教派
and formed a new faction.
他以自己的名字命名新的教派
He named this new sect after himself,
称之为"圣杜马教团"
calling it The Order of St. Dumas.
好吧  的确厉害
Okay. Impressive.
没错
Yes.
他的心智接受不了死而重生的事实
His psyche couldn't reconcile death and rebirth
直到我们给了他个更辉煌的身世
until we gave it a grander context.
...壮丽的大陆一角...
the epic corner of the land...
一个背景故事
A story.
他现在是阿泽瑞尔
He's Azrael now.
传说中12世纪为封建领主
A fabled 12th century knight who died
亚当·杜马战死的骑士
for the cause of his feudal Lord Adam Dumas.
这位杜马是一名圣人
This Dumas character was made a saint,
向世人展示过不少奇迹
performed a lot of miracles and so forth.
其中之一就是让阿泽瑞尔起死回生
And one of the miracles was bringing Azrael back to life.
我还是觉得氯丙嗪更好
I still prefer Thorazine.
你得学学如何利用手头上的资源  皮博迪女士
You need to learn to work with what you have, Ms. Peabody.
好吧
Okay.
我们的作品需要新的人格
Our creations need new personas
来充实丰满如今的自己
to equal and embody what they've become.
集中他们的精神
To give their minds focus.
也许  这就是盖勒文先生的命运吧
Perhaps, this was Mr. Galavan's destiny all along.
你怎么知道这人格能保持下去
How do you even know if the persona will hold?
只有一个办法能知道
There's only one way to find out.
我们派这头美丽的野兽出去
We send our beautiful monster out into the wild
并交给他一个简单的任务
with a simple task to perform.
他会需要套服装
He's going to need something to wear.
尼格玛先生  你还真是帮了大忙
Mr. Nygma, you have been... you've actually been helpful.
Mr. Nygma, you have actually been helpful.
打发  彻头彻尾的傲慢
Dismissal. The complete arrogance.
尼格玛先生  尼格玛先生  你还真是...
Mr. Nygma. Mr. Nygma, you have actually been...
犯人赫尔辛格
Inmate Helzinger,
跟我来
come with me.
是  女士
Yes, ma'am.
为什么他们总是消失在那条走廊尽头
Why do they keep disappearing down that hallway?
斯特兰奇在隐藏什么
Strange is hiding something.
你要带我去哪
Where are you taking me?
我们要去哪
Where are we going?
Where are we going?!
真有意思
How interesting.
快走
Move!
我认识你
Hey, I know you.
我给你带来一份礼物  孩子
I have a gift for you, my son.
我这会儿正在为你打造盔甲
I am crafting your armor as we speak,
但首先  得测试你的能力
but first, your skills must be tested.
我知道了
I got it.
你是市长
You're the mayor.
这是哪里
What is this place?
怎么...
What's going...?
那是一个恶魔
That is a demon.
-怎么回事  -他生于炼狱
- What's going on in here?-  He lives in fire.
我要离开这里
I want to get out of here!
那箱子里有能让你消灭他的武器
That case will give you everything you need to destroy him!
放我出去
Let me get out of here!
放我出去  放我出去
Let me out of here! Let me out!
我要离开这里  我要...
I want to get out of here! I want to...
虽然和我想的不大一样  但也不错了
Not exactly what I had in mind, but good enough.
试试...打开箱子  孩子
Try... opening the chest, my son.
罪孽之剑
The Sword of Sin.
这是你伸张正义的工具和伙伴
Your ally and instrument of justice,
世代流传  协助骑士铲除邪恶
a vanquisher of evil for generations.
它渴望鲜血
She thirsts for blood.
世代流传  这把剑是昨天刚做的
Generations? That sword was made yesterday.
无所谓
It doesn't matter.
这件复制品对他接受新身份很关键
Our replica is central to his acceptance of his new identity.
一件让人惊叹的标志性武器
An awe-inspiring signature weapon.
我要做什么
What must I do?
一个杀人犯现在自由在城市里游荡
A murderer walks the streets of this city a free man.
他的罪孽  必须被你的剑斩灭
For his sins, by your blade, he must be destroyed.
告诉我他的名字
Tell me his name.
詹姆斯·戈登
James Gordon.
我主
My lord.
我是死亡天使
I am the Angel of Death.
詹姆斯·戈登
James Gordon dies...
今晚必死
...tonight.
我的警官今晚早些时候
My officers responded to an anonymous tip
因匿名线报  前来接警
and arrived here earlier this evening.
进入建筑工地后
Upon entering the construction site,
我的手下发现了四名男性被害人的尸体
my men discovered the bodies of four male victims.
我们暂且还无从
It'll be some time before we have
查实他们的身份
any information about their identities.
我目前只能告诉大家这么多
That's all I have for you at this time.
失陪  就这些了
Excuse me. No, that's it.
警监  看我找到了谁
Hey, Cap, look who I found.
闭嘴  布洛克
Shut it, Bullock.
-你好大胆  -听着
- You have one hell of a nerve. - Listen...
你以为我不知道是你劫走了凯伦·詹宁斯
You think I don't know it was you that busted out Karen Jennings?
你倒说不是你
Tell me it wasn't you.
-警监  -我不想听
- Captain... - I don't want to hear it.
我为什么总是上你的当
How do I keep falling for your games?
真的  我简直搞不明白
Really, it's a mystery to me.
每次你回来
Every time you come back,
我都真的相信你已经变了
I truly believe that you've changed.
你就像视错觉
You're like a-an optical illusion.
我只需要跟你说五分钟的话
Listen I just need five minutes of your time.
哈格罗夫  司尼德
Hargrove! Snead!
马上护送戈登先生离开我的犯罪现场
Escort Mr. Gordon off my crime scene immediately.
你  明天早上我们要好好
You, we're gonna have a little discussion
就这事谈谈
about this tomorrow morning.
巴恩斯警监  请听他说完
Captain Barnes, please. Hear him out.
听着  孩子  韦恩先生
Listen, kid... Mr. Wayne,
我不管你有多少钱  在这城里多有地位
I don't care how much money or pull you have in this town.
我不想再跟他说话了
I'm through talking to him.
你也不想听真话了吗
Are you through listening to the truth?
得了  少来了
Oh, come on. Give me a break.
好吧  五分钟
All right, five minutes.
不  三分钟
No, three minutes.
阿卡姆疯人院
好了  发夹
Okay. Bobby pins?
只有一个吗
Only one?
我就偷到一个
It's all I could steal.
那就将就吧
It'll have to do.
鲁迪  弄到氨水了吗
Rudy, did you get the ammonia?
这儿
H-Here.
很好  好了
Perfect. Okay,
只差灭蚊灯了
now we just need the bug zapper.
这是什么
What is this?
是苍蝇拍
It's a fly swatter.
我知道是苍蝇拍
I can see that it's a fly swatter.
我没问你要苍蝇拍
I didn't ask for a fly swatter.
我要的是厨房里的灭蚊灯
I asked for the bug zapper in the kitchen.
有什么区别
What's the difference?
区别是
The difference is that
一个是发出紫外光的黑光灯
one has a black light that emits ultraviolet energy
这只是棍子加块皮子
and this is leather on a stick.
都能打苍蝇啊
They both kill flies.
我不是想打苍蝇
I don't need to kill flies.
我需要你回厨房去把灭蚊灯拿来
I need you to go back to the kitchen and get the bug zapper.
你要拿这些东西做什么啊
What are you gonna do with all this stuff, anyway?
我觉得斯特兰奇教授在隐瞒什么
I think Professor Strange is hiding something.
我觉得他隐瞒的是逃出这里的秘密通道
And I think that something is a secret way out of this dump.
所以我要用这堆东西找到它
So I'm gonna use this stuff to find it.
简而言之
So,in a nutshell,
雨果·斯特兰奇在忙里偷闲地
Hugo Strange is making monsters
拿死人制造怪物
out of dead people in his spare time,
而且他还让维克多·弗莱斯杀了凯伦·詹宁斯
and he had Karen Jennings killed by Victor Fries,
前者已经死了三个月了
who's been dead for three months.
我知道听上去很扯
I know it sounds far-fetched.
扯  不
Far-fetched? No.
简直疯了
It sounds insane!
但是真的  相信我
But it's true. Trust me.
你说这种疯话叫我怎么相信你
How can I trust you when you're talkin' crazy?
你对我撒了那么多谎叫我怎么相信你
How can I trust you when you've lied to me so many times?
怪物
Monsters?!
我骗你是因为对你说实话太难
I lied to you because it's hard to tell you the truth.
你固执  负气
You're stubborn and you're angry,
哥谭市警局已经因此付出了代价
and the GCPD has paid a price for it!
是吗  你个自以为是的混蛋
Really? You self-righteous punk.
你觉得你什么都知道吗
You think you have all the answers?
那你自己来管事啊
Maybe you should run it yourself!
或许我有天会的
Maybe I will one day.
做梦去吧
In your dreams.
谁在那儿
Who's there?
我说  谁在那儿
I said, who's out there?!
搞什么
What the hell?
詹姆斯·戈登
James Gordon.
你该赎罪了
The time for your penance has come.
你认识他吗
You know this guy?
你是谁
Who are you?
我是阿泽瑞尔  清理罪人的正义使者
I am Azrael, righteous scourge of sinners,
我是来杀你的  詹姆斯·戈登
and I have come to kill you, James Gordon.
放下武器
Put down that weapon!
Put the weapon down!
马上放下武器  否则我开枪了
Put it down right now or I'll shoot!
警监
Captain!
吉姆
Jim!
我现在就需要情报
I need information now.
我们对这人有什么了解
What do we know about this guy?
只知道你刚刚看到的  他自称阿泽瑞尔
Just what you saw. Calls himself Azrael.
想杀我
Wants to kill me.
我们知道是雨果·斯特兰奇搞的鬼
We know Hugo Strange is responsible.
他自己说的吗
Told you so, did he?
否则还能是谁
Who else could it be?
我不知道
I have no idea.
我得去查证事实
I have to find out the facts.
这就是做警察的乐趣
Fun part about being a police detective,
而不是个我行我素的义警
instead of a loose cannon vigilante.
抱歉  警监
Excuse me, Captain.
我觉得你无礼的态度很不合适
I find your flippant attitude to be inappropriate.
我还觉得你有点烦人呢
I find you to be kind of a pain in the ass.
他在这儿做什么
What's he even doing here?
我是位担心的市民
I'm a concerned citizen.
我想知道你打算采取什么措施
I want to know what you're doing about all of this.
你
You...
好吧
Well, uh...
我要集结突击队
I'm going to assemble the Strike Force,
召回不在岗人员
call in all off-duty personnel.
我们要撒网把这疯子找到
We're gonna dragnet the living daylights out of this wacko.
来自外太空的骑士应该挺好找  是吧
A knight from outer space shouldn't be too hard to find, right?
行吗
Okay?
我们就要这么办
That's what we're gonna do.
而你要回家
What you're gonna do is go home
别再插手警方事务了
and stop inserting yourself into police business.
-警监  -就这样了
- Captain... - That's the final word.
他说得对
He's right.
你该回家了
It's time you went home.
让警方和我来做剩下的事吧
Leave the rest of this to the police. And to me.
这事不止关系到警方
This is not just police business.
也和我有关
This is my business, too.
我不能采取必要行动的同时还得担心你
I can't make the moves I need to make if I'm worrying about you.
你得回家
You need to be at home,
让阿尔弗雷德照顾好你
where Alfred can look after you.
你好  格蕾丝
Hello, Grace.
你今天还好吗
How are you today?
难以置信的是  袭击者逃离了犯罪现场
Incredibly, the attacker fled the crime scene by,
并且不知为何  是沿大楼侧面攀爬了上去
for all intents and purposes, scaling the side of the structure,
消失在夜色之中
literally disappearing into thin air.
我做报道这么多年  肯  我得说
In all my years, Ken, I must say,
我还从未见过这样的事
I've never seen anything quite like it.
大胆逃亡
一个人类居然能做出这样的事
That a human being should be capable of such feats,
实在令人吃惊
it just astounds the mind.
盖勒文竞选市长
哥谭新市长  西奥·盖勒文
...Theo Galavan, the new mayor of Gotham!
得了  哥哥  我可是知道你从前的样子
Oh, brother, like I don't know you from way back.
记起来
Remember.
他自称阿泽瑞尔
He calls himself Azrael.
他持械  危险  并且表现出了
He's armed, dangerous, and has exhibited
异于常人的体能
some extraordinary physical abilities.
但是没人  绝对没人
But no one-- and I mean no one--
可以跑来我们的城市  动我的警官
comes into our city and tries to carve up my officers.
我们今晚要出去
We're gonna go out tonight,
仔细搜查每个街区
and we're gonna comb each and every block
直到找到这个戴面具的怪物
until we find this masked freak
把他关进监狱  他该去的地方
and put him behind bars where he belongs.
-有问题吗  -没有  长官
- Any questions? - No, sir!
很好  出去把他抓回来
Good. Now get out there and get him.
你干什么呢
What are you doing?
我要出去啊
I'm going out there.
-你去个鬼  -什么
- The hell you are. - Excuse me?
你要待在这里  这是对你的保护
You're staying here for your own protection.
这是命令
That's an order.
我不是警察了  记得吗
I'm not a cop anymore, remember?
我不需要听从你的命令了
I don't need to follow your orders.
你说得太对了
You're absolutely right.
你俩  把戈登先生关起来
You two, put Mr. Gordon here in lockup.
-什么  -我要以
- What? - I'm holding you
涉嫌劫囚凯伦·詹宁斯羁押你
on suspicion of breaking Karen Jennings out of GCPD custody.
别这么做
Don't do this!
我已经做了
I've already done it.
莎士比亚故事
亚瑟王
有这么多故事可以选择
So many stories to choose from.
爱丽丝镜中世界奇遇记
我感觉好像圣诞节早晨的孩子
I feel like a child on Christmas morning.
-你要见我  -是的
- You wanted to see me? - Yes.
我想立刻给更多实验对象灌输人格
I want to install personas into more subjects immediately.
我们为之努力的一切终于近在咫尺了
Everything we've worked for is finally within reach.
"但我不想去与疯子为伍"  爱丽丝说
"'But I don't want to go among mad people,' Alice remarked.
"这可没办法"  猫说
"'Oh, you can't help that,' said the Cat:
"我们可都是疯子"
'We're all mad here.'"
很好
Oh, yes.
这本就很好
Yes, that will do nicely.
搜索尚无新情况
No news from the search.
放我出去
Let me out of here.
这是为了你好
This is for your own good.
相信我  你今天犯的法够多了
Trust me, you've broken enough laws for one day.
有时候犯法才是正确的做法
There are times when breaking the law is the right thing to do.
这要谁来决定呢  你吗
And who gets to decide that, you?
是的  总得有人来决定
Yeah. Someone has to.
不  吉姆  你错了
No, Jim, you're wrong.
看看哥谭在往什么方向发展
Look where Gotham's going.
疯子  变态  怪物都从各个地方爬出来
Maniacs, perverts, freaks, crawling out of every hole.
就好像一股邪恶的海洋淹没了城市
It's like a sea of evil flooding the city.
如果人不抓紧法律
If a man doesn't cling on to the law,
就会失去方向  会淹死
he'll lose his bearings, drown.
灯怎么回事
What gives with the lights?
停电了
Everything's down.
停电
Blackout?
我看不是
I don't think so.
我也觉得
Yeah, me neither.
詹姆斯·戈登
James Gordon.
靠着囚室  快点
Back up against the cell! Move!
我是哥谭市警局的巴恩斯警监
This is Captain Barnes of the GCPD!
不管你是谁
Whoever you are,
走到灯光下  否则我们会干掉你的
step into the light or we will take you out!
但我就是光明
But I am the light,
我肩负消灭那囚室中的邪恶的使命
tasked with vanquishing the evil in that cell.
你可以拼死一试
You can die tryin'!
你是他们的领袖  我愿跟你谈判
You lead these men, so I will parley with you.
谈判
Parley?
命令他们退下  让罪人詹姆斯·戈登
Order them to stand aside and allow the sinner, James Gordon,
受到惩罚
to be punished.
照做  我就放过他们的命
Do this, and I will spare them all.
拒绝  他们就要面对我的审判
Decline and they will face my judgment.
他们的命现在在你手上了
Their lives now rest in your hands.
会死几个人呢
How many will die?
全部  还是一个
All? Or one?
决定吧  警监
Decide, Captain.
你下地狱去吧
You can go to hell.
我去过那儿了
I've been there.
你去吧
You go.
那里
Over there!
你看到他了吗
Do you see him?
他哪去了
Where'd he go?
我不知道  看到他了吗
I don't know. You got eyes on him?
把他弄出来
Get him out of there!
好惊人的毁灭工具
Such an amazing tool of destruction.
邪恶的法术
Vile sorcery.
我们需要更大的枪
We need a bigger gun.
是啊
Yeah.
我把这怪物引去楼上
I'm gonna lure the freak up the stairs.
你找个能把这混蛋撕个洞的东西来
Then you show up with something that'll tear a hole in this bastard.
好嘞
You got it.
我们快去屋顶
Let's get to the roof right now!
你
You,
你带我去见他
you will show me to him.
告诉我他在哪
You will tell me where he is.
然后呢
And then what?
你就放过我一命吗
You'll spare my life?
这已经太迟了
It's too late for that.
我最多只能让你死得没有痛苦
The most I can offer you is a painless death.
我们玩玩吧
Let's dance.
这不可能
That-that is not possible.
是你
You.
你死了
You're dead.
又活了
Not anymore.
总算来了
Finally.
过来吧
Come to me,
我会送你下地狱
and I will show you the way to hell.
我认识路
I know the way.
如果您刚刚打开电视  我们正在
For those just joining us, we're coming to you live
哥谭市警局外为您现场直播
from outside of the Gotham City Police Department...
哥谭市警局发生枪战
-天呐  -我身后发生了
- Oh, my God. - There-there's been a major
重重的撞击  车辆...
impact behind me. The vehicle...
有个人掉了下来
It appears a body has fallen...
-西奥·盖勒文  -西奥·盖勒文
- Theo Galavan. - Theo Galavan.
-真是他  -是他
- It's really him. - It's him!
-西奥·盖勒文身着...  -天呐
- Theo Galavan wearing... - Oh, my God...
盖勒文...
...Galavan.
好吧  再说一次
Right. Uh, once again,
我们确认前哥谭市市长
we are confirming that the former mayor of Gotham City,
西奥·盖勒文还活着  并且身着
Theo Galavan, is alive and dressed in a...
一套怪异的服装
bizarre costume.
老大
Boss.
这城市真是越来越疯狂了  是吧  吉姆
It's getting crazy in this town, huh, Jim?
别说话  保持呼吸
Don't talk. Just breathe.
我在呼吸呢
I'm tryin'.
-你不会有事的  -是啊
- You're gonna be okay. - Sure, I am.
你真是个烦人鬼  知道吗
You're a pain in the ass, you know that?
你也不是省油的灯
That makes two of us.
老大  呼吸
Boss, breathe!
加油  警监
Come on, Captain.
撑住  别睡过去
Hold on. Stay with me.
老大
Boss...
血压下降很快  我们得走了  呼叫哥谭总院
BP's falling fast. We got to go now. Radio Gotham General.
让他们知道这边情况
Let 'em know we're coming in hot!
吉姆  吉姆  怎么回事
Jim! Jim! What the hell happened?
-你没事吧  -嗯
- You okay? - Yeah.
是盖勒文
It was Galavan.
你确定
You sure?
我知道很难置信
I know it's hard to believe.
但阿泽瑞尔就是盖勒文
But Azrael is Galavan.
芭芭拉
Barb.
这样有点烦人啊
That's a little irritating.
抱歉
Sorry.
亲爱的
Babes.
放松
Relax.
不  我
No, I...
你们对我真好
You guys have been so good to me.
没事的  别担心
That's okay. Don't worry.
鸡尾酒
Cocktails.
我特别会调鸡尾酒
I make great cocktails.
好啊  那也不错
Sure. That'd be nice.
你们想喝什么
What do you want?
波本
Uh, bourbon on...
-螺丝锥  -加冰
- Gimlets! - ...the rocks.
-其实  波本就...  -我要做螺丝锥
- Actually, bourbon sou... - I'm making gimlets.
好吧  她让我害怕
Okay, she scares me.
别怂了  她无害的
Don't be a baby. She's harmless.
亲爱的  我知道你喜欢她
Honey, I know you like her,
但那女人疯透顶了
but that woman's mad as a bag of squirrels.
她说她都治好了
She said she's cured.
疯子就会这么说
That's what an insane person would say.
我们有酸橙吗
Do we have any limes?
没有
No.
天呐
Oh, my God.
没错  唐  今晚早些时候
That's right, Don. The masked assassin
袭击了哥谭市警局的蒙面人
that attacked the GCPD earlier tonight
已经确认为前市长西奥·盖勒文
has been identified as former mayor Theo Galavan.
有报道称
Now, there were reports...
西奥  不可能啊
Theo? It can't be.
老天爷
Holy moly.
袭击者被逼下了屋顶
...the assassin was forced off the roof,
然后跌落下来
then fell right over there,
之后他当着所有人的面站了起来
then stood up in front of all of us.
是他  西奥·盖勒文  他还活着
And it was him, Theo Galavan, alive.
据我们所知
And from what we know,
他杀死了三位警官
he's responsible for three officer fatalities.
我们还得知
We also learned that...
你好啊  老朋友
Hello, old friend.
仍逍遥在外  并被视为极度危险
...still at large and is considered extremely dangerous.
他肯定
Well, he must...
根本没死  否则不可能啊
never have been dead. I mean, that's the only possibility.
没有人能死而复生  是吧
I mean, no one dies and comes back to life again, do they?
没人能
No one.
但他复活了
But he did.
斯特兰奇
Strange.
肯定是斯特兰奇搞的鬼
Strange must be behind this.
什么  我们城市上演的惨剧吗
What... the hell is happening to our city?
反正不是好事
Nothing good.
阿卡姆疯人院
不  我不想走
No, no, I don't want to go.
我们就是去见...
We're just going to see...
天呐
Oh, my.